(upbeat music)
- Hey everyone, welcome to another episode of Little Fish.
This is the bonus Monday episode
where we put down our favorite facts
from the last seven days and we go through all of yours.
We get to sit back and enjoy them.
Thank you for sending them in.
My name is Dan Schreiber.
I'm sitting here with Andrew Hunter Murray
and James Harkin.
We've got a great batch this week.
So why don't we get straight into it?
Who wants to go first?
- I will.
I've got one here from Sort.
And it is about the FIFA World Cup,
which is now all over.
But I think we might have a few sort of stragglers
in the FIFA World Cup facts.
- This is to wean people off
your excitement of what we've gone through.
- Just to give people a bit of inside knowledge.
When you email in, if it's a good fact
and it's going to be in Little Fish, hopefully,
that will be in about eight weeks' time.
Actually, this is about the FIFA World Cup 2002.
So it must be that's when they sent it.
Now, actually, it's about all of the World Cups,
I would say, certainly the more recent ones.
And it is about the hometown of this person
called CLCOT in Pakistan.
And CLCOT manufactures all the balls used in the World Cup.
So Pakistan is always represented at the tournament
even though the men's team is ranked 198th in the world.
- Oh.
- And CLCOT also manufactures the most bagpipes in the world
outside of the United Kingdom.
So it's all pipes and pipes and balls.
- Lethery containers.
- I guess they are, yeah.
- You could, in extremists, use a squished football
to be the bag for a bagpipe.
You know what I mean?
Like Jam, do a sort of trakiotomy on it.
Jam in the pipes.
- Very true.
- That would be exciting.
- Bice versa.
- Absolutely.
It's Scotland's first ever World Cup final.
But oh no, there's been a mix up with the delivery
from Pakistan.
So you're going to have to play with the bagpipe.
Guys, yes.
- No, I like, you know, it's a really good concept.
But I think you have to suspend belief a little bit
for Scotland getting to the final World Cup.
(laughing)
- Sorry, Scotland.
So yeah, this place, the industry began in 1889
in this Pakistani town.
When a British sergeant asked a local saddlemaker
to repair a damaged football.
It's kind of been an industrial town for a long time
and they just have really good artisans,
really good sewers and stuff.
And because handsome balls are way better
than machine sewn ones.
- Are they?
- Yeah.
- Okay, Andy, if you go on.
- Yes, this is a fantastic one.
Okay, so it's from Elise Liu.
And I'm going to give it to you in the form of a riddle.
- Okay. - Okay.
- So I'm standing on black-fronted bridge
overlooking the river Thames.
- Yes.
- And I'm in London.
- Okay.
- What country am I in?
- Oh.
- The United Kingdom of Great Britain,
Northern Ireland.
(burps)
- You're in those places that rebuild the world
in a small little town.
- Are you in London, Manitoba or wherever it is?
- Ontario. - Ontario.
- London Ontario is a town of about half a million people
between Toronto and Detroit
in a bit of Canada sticking down between the Great Lakes.
And Elise has just provided
what they have in London brackets Canada.
- Yeah.
- They've got the River Thames.
They've got Coffin Garden Market.
They've got Black Forest Bridge, Victoria Park,
Foxall Park, Oxford Street, Pickley Street, Palmael,
Kensington Avenue, Rita the Treet.
- They should get their own stuff.
(laughs)
- Why they stealing our stuff.
- They've got Westminster Hyde Park, Lambeth,
to name three of the Jules of London brackets original.
- Oh really?
- I just love it.
- Have they got Hackney Fried Chicken?
(laughs)
- And also, this is the weird thing.
It is a crucible of Canadian
celebrity talent.
- Oh, I thought you were going to say
crucible of Canadian witch burning.
(laughs)
- Oh.
- Celine Dion?
- Well, why don't I tell you?
- Ah, it's for a set.
- I'll get it again.
- Just in Bieber.
- Okay, yes, granted.
But.
(laughs)
Elise provides a list of people.
- Okay.
- And I think there is quite a clear,
fame and meridian, which we pass.
At some point to the list, I'm not going to tell you when.
- Okay.
- All right.
These people were all born in London, Ontario.
The Beeps.
- Justin Bieber.
- Yeah.
- Ryan Gosling.
- Rachel McCadams.
- Yep.
- Victor Garber.
- Paul Haggis.
(laughs)
- I didn't even invent the Haggis.
- I invented the Haggis.
- Pakistani man, actually.
(laughs)
But, yeah.
- Actually, the one before Paul Haggis,
I wasn't aware of.
- Yeah.
- Victor Garber, I think, is a producer.
- Okay.
- Oh, the former.
The ones that perform the ones that produce it.
But I would say the fame and meridian is between Bieber
and Garber.
- Okay.
- Yeah.
- Of course, they didn't stay there forever.
- Paul, which is in Ontario.
And Rachel McCadams went off to York University, brackets.
- Toronto, Ontario.
(laughs)
- Very good.
- Yeah.
- Thank you, Elise.
- Lovely fact.
- Very good.
I'm gonna take us over to Dublin.
Dublin, Ontario.
- Dublin.
(laughs)
- No, we're in Dublin now.
This is from Michael McLaughlin.
And he says, "Thought you might enjoy this."
And this is new news.
So this is sort of topical.
The hole in the wall, pub and Dublin,
was recently issued a closure order
because there were holes in the wall.
(laughs)
- Have we been to this pub?
I feel like I have been there.
- I haven't been there.
I think I'd know that we've been there.
Purely because it is the longest pub in Europe.
It stretches 100 meters long.
- No.
- Yeah, it wraps around this whole road.
On this site, it says it's 153 meters.
And then other places, it says it's 100 meters.
- But how is it deep?
- Yeah, it's just long.
- No, once you're inside, if it's long,
isn't it deep and correct?
- No, it's long pub going all the way along the road, right?
- Yeah.
- How deep is it from the back?
Is it like six feet deep, but 100 meters long?
- I think I don't understand what deep means.
- What do you mean?
- In a three-dimensional look.
- Yeah.
- Jesus Christ, right.
- Look at the bed out.
- The pub is 100 meters long, right?
- Yeah.
- Which is what I said.
- That's what you said.
And there's no problem there.
But is it a shallow pub?
- Oh, it is only like that.
- I don't have the dimensions on its width.
- How tall is it?
- I think it's largely one floor with a mezzanine bit.
- Didn't expect you to do that.
Very impressive.
- I know.
But it's been shut down because they had a problem
with rat droppings and so on.
So hygiene levels have not been great.
That was part of the holes of the wall.
- The holes in the wall mean that that's
where the access points are for all of the rodents
that are getting in.
- It's not entirely because of the holes in the wall.
- It's a two-parter.
It was rats and holes with the two things.
- I've been to what was claimed to be the longest bar
in, I'm gonna say the world, but it could be Europe.
And this is the actual bar itself,
not the length of the pub.
- Oh yeah.
- And that was bar one in Sheffield.
- Ah.
- And also, while I was there,
I broke the world record for the biggest round
ever sold as in, what?
- How many did you buy?
- I didn't buy them.
- No, I was part of the, I was a recipient
of one of the drinks.
- When you say I broke the record,
it did sound like...
- There were 10,000 people here, James.
- Yeah, I said I'll get it.
- Yeah, it's fine.
- Let's go on the company, can't we?
- I don't wanna.
- Well, that's really impressive, don't we?
- Very cool.
- The wall.
- Yeah, it had a name before.
It became the hole in the wall.
There's a rumor that it became...
- It's called the rat shit party.
(laughing)
- I'm sure it's a great pub.
- I did that.
- I think, I'm pretty sure I've been there
and I'm pretty sure it is awesome.
- Yeah, nice, yeah.
And one of the thoughts is why it was given its new name.
The hole in the wall is because of the local army barracks
around, they're not allowed on license premises.
So they were thought that there might be holes
that they could sell them the alcohol through.
- That's clever.
- No.
- No, it's just a theory.
- Might be.
- All right, let's get another.
- Okay, this one is from John Kelly
and John was walking down the South Downs.
So back in Good old Blighty,
not the South Downs in New Zealand, or whatever.
And John was curious about how many skeletons lay under his feet.
And it turned out that according to John's calculations,
there was roughly one between one and five quadrillion skeletons.
- Huh.
- Oh, we're talking like animal carcass and insect carcass.
We're talking cock-o-lift carcass.
Because this is chalk and chalk is made
of billions of microscopic skeletons and John did the maths.
And that's how many?
Five quadrillion maximum?
- I don't know what a quadrillion is that?
Is that just beneath him, or is it the whole of the...
- If?
- I think it must be not just like the outline of his feet.
- I'm going to draw.
- No, no, no, don't try it.
- Right, this is now not the problem.
- This is now the white cliffs of Dover.
- It's John walking along.
- Yeah, okay.
- Okay.
Has that helped you James with Andy's question?
- Neil Buchanan's shitting himself.
That's what it's like.
(laughing)
For "International Nevermind" though.
- So yeah, these are just cock-o-lifts.
They create protective shell known as the cock-o-sphere.
And when they die, they sink down to the bottom of the ocean
and they turn into chalk.
And that's what the white cliffs of Dover are made from.
- It is pretty cool.
- It's pretty metal.
- It's amazing just to think of how many billions
of living creatures made those cliffs.
- Yeah, yeah.
- For you to just draw a shitty picture of them.
- Interesting.
It's hard seeing your art criticized,
but I'm going to say that was fair.
(laughing)
- Andy, yes, it was fair.
- All right, here's one.
This is from John Cornwall, brackets, Ontario.
- Is it really?
- No, John Cornwall, that's his name.
- Oh, it's his name.
- It was just, this is a very interesting fact, I think.
I saw a post yesterday about someone that was on a cruise
that set off the day before.
They saw someone reading that day's newspaper
and asked how nervous they had got it.
Maybe a drone delivery or a paper boy
who'd invested in a speedboat, turns out that some
of the larger cruise boats, I believe they call them liners,
have a printing press on board
and they print a slim-down version of some newspapers.
- That's really cool.
- This may be common knowledge, but I found it amazing.
I thought some of your listeners might as well.
And I know that for Dan, who has an special interest in
printing out things and putting the date on the top,
and whether that's a wasteful policy,
you might like to know that.
I think that's a great, that's an amazing idea.
'Cause I've, and I've got personal experience of this,
'cause I've done a void from Southampton to New York.
- Yeah.
- And they had something like three copies
of the times available for the whole ship.
- I did, Dave.
- Because.
- So whoever gets it first, it does the crossword.
It's for everyone.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
- See what I'd like to do for cruises is a predictive newspaper,
where you pre-print every day of the voyage
with the news you think is gonna happen
and how things are gonna play out.
So everyone-- - Oh my God, ship it.
Iceberg.
(laughing)
- What the hell?
No survivors of it.
- But you live in this bubble of this,
this news that gets passed around
and then you get off on the other side
and you find out how different it was.
- The ones that TV show called "The Bubble"
wasn't meant to remember, it was very short lived.
I think it did really well in another country,
like Netherlands or something.
But they brought it here and they put celebrities in a bubble
and then after a week, they asked some questions about the news,
which obviously everyone at home would know.
- Right.
- But they wouldn't know because they were in the bubble.
- That's quite good.
- It's quite a good idea, but it didn't work at all.
- What was the TV show with the guy
got the tomorrow's paper delivered to his door every day?
- Really?
- Yeah, there was an old American series
and basically he got a paper delivered.
He never saw who delivered it.
He was always rushing to the door saying,
"Who's delivered this?"
And it was tomorrow's paper and it was all the awful things
that would happen in the city.
- And he'd have to try and stop it.
- He didn't have to run around and stop it.
- I think at the end of the episode,
he'd actually see the paper that ended up being printed
and it was always better because he'd saved the day.
- Yeah, it was like building, doesn't burn down.
- Right.
- Or whatever.
- I'd never heard of that.
- It's a fantastic show.
I'm gonna have to look at it.
I wonder how many things you could get to in a day
to prevent.
- It's not a whole newspaper's worth, you know?
It's just the front page, right?
- Would you choose the one which did the best good
for the whole city or the one which was closest?
And you were more likely to be able to do something to save.
- Yeah, I might put in a few calls for the ones
that were let say on the other side of the river.
- Yeah.
- I might just ring up and say,
by the way, there's an atrocity's gonna happen.
- The problem is that if you ring up and say
that atrocity's gonna happen,
then you're directly implicated in that atrocity.
- Oh yeah, this guy is always being arrested.
- Making bombswriters and stuff, day three,
he's most wanted man in America.
- I'm probably completely bunch of the explanation
of the series, wait, I gotta find out.
- Sounds a bit like Quantum Leap, doesn't it?
- Do you know what?
I think it was shown in a double bill with Quantum Leap.
I seem to remember that.
It was called Early Edition, 1990's supernatural drama.
Yes, it was on for four years from 1996 to 2000.
The user's knowledge to prevent terrible events.
- Do you think someone sent him an email
the day before it got cancelled?
- Say it at the point.
(laughing)
(upbeat music)
- Here's one that's come in from Alex Nelson.
Alex Nelson says, "Sir Christopher Ren
"has a single IMDB credit.
"Art Department on a 2013 episode of Question Time."
(laughing)
- And I looked it up and it's there.
- That's very good.
- It's very good.
- It was basically held in one of his buildings.
- It was filmed in Symbols Cathedral
and he is listed as set designer in the credits.
(laughing)
And I tried to find more because it's actually quite hard
to find on IMDB who's gonna be listed.
So you just have to chuck some names in and hope it lands.
- We're trying to find particular architects.
- I looked so Frank Lloyd Wright.
He's got a credit for Cliff House designer.
But then you have things like in 2014,
Sigmund Freud was named a spiritual consultant on a movie.
But that's on IMDB.
It's an official credit for Sigmund.
They all have, I mean, everyone does have it
'cause they appears there self, don't they,
an archive for it's weird when you see Hitler's IMDB
and there's six listings of thanks, you know.
- What?
(laughing)
- That's where it gets a bit strange.
- What do you know what they are?
Can you remember them?
- Some of them were ironic.
- Surely is.
Oh right, okay.
- Frank Araplane has enlisted as worst boy.
(laughing)
That kind of thing.
- That's such a good joke.
- But I did see, I put Rosa Parks's name in there
because last little fish that the three of us were on,
she came up as a part of potentially it being on predator.
And she has a lot of self and she has a lot of thanks,
but she also has a credit for a show.
She was in an episode playing herself.
- I know I know this.
- As if it was in Only Fools and Horses, wasn't she?
- She just didn't want us to play as best.
- Yes.
- It was really funny.
- She gets engaged to Del Boy.
- Yeah.
- And then the whole caper that leads to the falling apart.
- Can we guess it?
- It's an American drama, early edition.
(laughing)
- Imagin' if that was right.
- Yeah.
- Like he reads the news of this civil rights project
and he's like, I must stop this.
- Now you see me far.
(laughing)
- No, it's a show.
- I knew growing up in Hong Kong was on TV all the time,
touched by an angel.
- I was about to guess speed,
'cause I was trying to think of other great buzzer-based.
- I, yeah, spice welded movie.
(laughing)
- Summer holiday with Clifford Tid and Rosa Parks.
- Do you think her agent was always calling her up going?
There's a real amazing ceremony going on in your honor.
You're up for it, great.
We've also got an offer from Keanu Reeves and Speed.
(laughing)
- No, okay, I'm just checking.
I just always like to check with you.
I always like to check.
Yeah, she was in an episode of Touch by an Angel,
which was an America.
- Yeah, I don't remember that one.
- It's hard to describe, but those kind of--
- Is it like an angel who, basically does the same
as all these American dramas used to do,
which is something dramatic is happening
and then someone has a superpower that helps them to solve.
- Yeah.
- I think it might have been, I can't remember,
but it's not a drama as in Dallas,
where it was like on every day.
It was more like party of five or whatever that,
however those American things are.
Anyway, she's got that.
- Brilliant.
- Yeah, so anyway, congrats to Christopher Ren.
- Okay, here's one from Shen Flindel.
And they write, "If the Rubik's Cube World Record Holder
and the Blindfold Cube World Record Holder
solved the same scramble,
the Blindfold Salver would probably be finished
before the regular Salver had even started."
- Oh.
- Good, good, good, good, good, good.
- What's going on?
See it, you can start, right?
As in when you get the cube, you just go,
you just go, well, no.
What happens is when you get the cube,
you have 15 seconds to look at it
and work out what you're gonna do
and then work out what all the moves are gonna do
and then you go, "Go!"
and you go, (shushing)
and you make it, okay?
The blindfold record is 11.67 seconds,
but in that rule, you basically, you get it,
you look at it, and then as soon as you're ready,
then you put the blindfold on and then you solve it.
So you're allowed to start before the 15 seconds.
- Oh, we're getting in.
- So that's why he would always have beaten this guy
called Charlie Eggins, who's the blindfolded guy,
would have beaten it before Teodor Zyder and Poland,
would have done his, because of just the rules.
In actual fact, Teodor Zyder could do it quicker,
but in the rules, he has to wait his 50 seconds.
- Yeah, I know, 'cause James, you can solve a Rubik's cube,
and you can do it really fast, but you can do it,
I can't do it at all. - Sure.
- So... - Much faster than that.
- Yeah.
(all laughing)
You just try every one of the 50 billion possible places
it can be, and that eventually comes in.
- And then you get it. - False measure.
- Yeah, so my question is that if you're blindfolded,
is the time that you're given that's extra looking at it,
it's because there is a set way of just turning it right
until you get there.
So you've got to work out how many of those moves are,
'cause no one's going to stop you if you get it.
If you go past it, presumably in the blind version
of solving it, you just keep going past the final configuration.
- I see what you mean.
Yeah, you might do that, but I mean,
I don't have the brain capacity or exactly the understanding
to do it, so I don't know exactly how it works,
but I think it would be pretty unlikely for you
to get the final configuration then go past it.
- It should could go one or two.
- But you can't think of it, right?
- Yeah, someone's just standing by.
- Coffing. - Scream.
- Stop, stop, the God thing, stop.
- No, you can't say it, but you would just know,
like, 'cause you know what order all the moves are in.
So the final section of moves,
where you're getting the final pieces in,
that will always be the last move you make,
will always be one of those.
- Oh, no.
- Because of the configuration changes, yes, I see.
- So you would, I guess it's possible you could get just past it,
but you would never be miles past it.
- Well, there's one behind,
there's one is literally behind you on the shelf down,
so let's just, let's just, you just,
you just, you just start doing it now.
- No, no, no, we're gonna get down to do it.
- This only needs one turn to be complete, so.
- Welcome to the next 50 hours of your life.
(laughing)
- This is a rich and herring special,
maybe it's cube, yeah.
- Done.
- Wow, I think that was even faster than you could do it.
- I think honestly was, yeah.
- Okay, interesting, amazing.
- Very, very cool.
- The record for solving a Rubik's cube was done by.
- Rubik?
- No, Wimben, the.
- Correct, first letter.
- Rrrrrrr.
- Right from my heavens.
- Correct.
- London, Ontario.
- That's right.
- No, it's robot.
- Oh, it is.
- A robot can now do it in 103 milliseconds.
- Wow.
- And for reference, it takes you between
200 and 300 milliseconds to blink.
So if you're watching a robot do it in the cube,
it will be definitely possible for you to blink
and it'll just have happened when you were bunking.
- How would it not shatter the cube?
- They're special, yeah, they're.
- Reinforced and extra lubricated.
- They're very lubricated, yeah.
- Yeah, okay.
- 'Cause you can buy Rubik's cube, can't you?
- Cube, cube, they call it, that's right.
- My son and I, Ted, were trying to say super-califragilistic,
S.B. Ali Doshis as quick as possible the other day.
And we tried to see whether or not
it's possible that you can bunch them up so tightly
that you can just go S.B.
And if you slowed down the audio,
it would break down into the entire word.
And I wonder if that's possible.
- It's really nice that you've found someone
that saved that to level as you to have conversations.
- We're actually setting up a rival podcast to finish soon.
- Oh, we're done in the water Andy.
With that kind of chat, oh my god.
- Don't they also like soap up Rubik's cube?
Are you allowed to, are you?
- You can loop them.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
- Bring your loop to the cube.
- This is why you weren't allowed on that I.C.P. game show.
(laughing)
- Bring your loop to the cube with dad's driver.
- I didn't know it used to be Philips Scarfield who hosted that.
- Was it?
- The cube.
- I don't remember.
- I think it was.
- I think we've done as the Philips Scarfield of Fish.
- Oh, that's very sweet.
- Okay Andy, go on, give us another fact.
- Here's one more fact about Canadian geography.
- Oh, I don't.
- I just love this so much.
This is a wonderful name.
Clementine Curly from Melbourne.
- Melbourne.
- Australia?
- Australia.
- Actually, Clementine doesn't say.
Could be Melbourne, Ontario.
Clementine writes, "I recently learned,
"are you familiar with the actor Nathan Filion?"
- No.
- He was in Buffy, he was in Firefly and Serenity.
- Oh, I think I know who he is.
- Probably no.
- Yeah, he's a great actor, really good.
Anyway, Nathan Filion has a little park lit dedicated to him
in his hometown of Edmonton, Canada,
which is called the Nathan Filion, civilian-pavilion.
(laughing)
- That's really good.
- And is painted with a million.
- Is it really?
- Yeah, that is great.
- That's brilliant.
(laughing)
- Well, that is fantastic.
But that's enough of your facts for now.
We can't wait to read more of them out next week.
But before we wrap up today's show,
we love to hand out one of our old facts
to members of Club Fish.
So if you join on patreon.com/clubfish
at the highest here, which is friend of the podcast,
we assign you one of the headline facts
from the last 12 years of fish.
You get a really cool digital certificate along with it.
And we like to read out who's got what.
So we're gonna do some now, who wants to go first?
- I'll do one.
This one goes out to Sveinung Carlson.
Sveinung, congratulations to you.
Your fact is, if you grow cause lettuce in a spaceship,
it tastes like rocket.
- Perfect.
- Brilliant facts.
- Because they did it, and it does.
They must have, when they first tasted that cause lettuce,
they must have thought, we've blown this shit wide open.
(laughing)
- Or if you're in America, it tastes like a rugula.
- Oh yeah, but it doesn't work quite as well.
- The joke doesn't work.
- No.
(laughing)
- I've got another one here about vegetables.
- Oh yeah.
- This is that the National Giant vegetable championship
had to move venue in the mid-1980s
as the Pumpkins started getting too big
to fit through the doors.
And that now is under the custodianship of Heather Klein.
- Love it.
- Oh my god, I love this fact so much.
- Yeah, remember that.
Do you remember we did quite a lot on big vegetables
in the Pumpkins and stuff?
- This is not meaning to sound like a joke,
it was the low-hanging fruit of its time.
I mean, just giant vegetable growing compositions,
I'd just wonderfully funny things
and the people who run them are brilliant.
All right, let's get another one out here.
This goes to Michael Luna.
Your fact is the bearded lacewing insect
incapacitates its prey by farting on it.
- Oh.
(laughing)
- That's nice.
- That's gonna look nice on your wall frame.
(laughing)
- It's a conversation piece like all of these are.
- There it is, it is.
- They stun termites 30 times their size
with anal vapor.
- That's incredible.
- That's like me knocking out an elephant with a fart.
- Yes.
- I would like to see that.
- Right.
- You'd have to get your bum right up to the elephant's nose.
- Well, it's got a movable trunk there.
- Yeah.
- That's the trunk is, yeah, yeah.
- Yeah, you picked a good animal there.
(laughing)
- How'd you encourage the elephant
to get its trunk near your bum though?
- Put a peanut.
(laughing)
- Well.
- I just think, I hope no poachers are listening
to this because we're giving them too many good ideas.
(laughing)
- Put a peanut in it.
- Brilliant.
Here's another one.
This one goes out to Harry.
Harry, your fact is that Ruby, a sheep
which had been genetically engineered
to glow in the dark was accidentally sold to an abattoir.
(laughing)
- Oh, lovely.
Another nice one to go.
- I know.
- This was an animal effect.
- Was it?
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
- Ruby's mother had been given this team.
- And for the nicest woman you'll meet,
she does come here with some dodgy facts, doesn't she?
- She remembers the one about the bear
who they had to castrate them
because they'd been having sex with the family members
or whatever it was.
- That's right.
It was a sort of incest.
- That's fair, Romania or somewhere.
- That's right.
- Yeah.
- No, I know.
I mean, well, she likes crime, doesn't she?
She likes murder.
- Oh yeah.
- That's true.
- Infectional terms.
Anyway, congratulations on Harry.
That's a lovely fact.
Okay, here is another fact.
This one goes under the custodianship of Zachary Nichols.
Zachary, your fact, is that during the launch of BBC Two,
in 1964, a live kangaroo got stuck in a lift
at television center.
- Sure.
(laughs)
- Brilliant.
- I pretended to sort of be stuck in a lift
with the comedian Barry Cryer.
- Oh yeah.
- So I kept sending us to the wrong floor
so that I just got more time with him
to get more chatting with him.
- Did he?
- Yeah, so we went up, we went down,
we're like, "Oh, no, this is not it.
What's going on?"
- Kind of thing.
And I milked it for quite some time
because he was also confusing building, isn't it?
And I thought, which it was, wasn't it?
- It was a confusing building, yeah.
It feels like that's kidnapping.
- Yeah.
- A pensioner as well.
- When you frame it in a negative way.
- Yeah.
- Yeah, I can see how that might.
(laughs)
- Let's do another one.
This one is going to Jay Now.
Your factor is Dr. Seuss once wrote a Warner Brothers film
that was banned because it accidentally predicted
the Manhattan project.
- Brilliant.
- A lot going on in there, yep.
Talk to Seuss wrote a film that was banned by Warner Brothers.
- How can you accidentally predict the most complicated
human endeavor ever created?
I guess you just have to predict it a bit, don't you?
- Yeah, you don't have to be like,
"First this walk, it goes in this side case,
"then this goes boom, and this goes doom,
"and loads of rooms."
- Oh my God, that is quite good.
- That is good.
- Before he was a children's author,
he worked in the writing department for the military,
didn't he?
He wrote a lot of movies and so on.
So he must have written something
that just was a bit too close.
- He also wrote one with loads of naked characters,
and it didn't he, do you remember that?
- Did he?
- Yeah.
But then it was illustrated in the same way
as his normal books, don't remember that one.
Here's one that goes out to Robert Dixon.
- Robert, your fact, now and forever is,
the phrase, "Why is my poop green?"
Is Google most commonly between five and six a.m.
- Yeah.
- It doesn't make sense.
- It does.
- There are peaks and troughs of when you're Googling things.
- Yeah, people are most likely to find out
after a long sleep, maybe.
- Five and six in the morning, quite early.
- Why?
- Feels like these people
were having a long dark night at the salt.
- I think you've had a night poo, it's been green.
You thought that's probably normal.
You've woken up at four.
You've spent an hour freaking out and then you've Googled.
- Interesting.
- That's something just for it, just as an example
of how that might happen.
- Yeah, I think this was just like,
Google had released a load of data
about when people search for different things
and what was the most searched item in that year
and whatever and this was the funniest part of it.
- Oh God, you had a follow-up effect on this one James.
There's a percentage of people Googling lonely peaks
at 3.24 a.m.
- Yeah.
- 'Cause I don't want to wait until 3.25 a.m.
- Hold off.
- It's not a very social hour.
3.a.m.
- No, that's really normal.
- The reason you're lonely is 'cause everyone else is asleep.
(laughing)
Okay, the final one for today goes now
under the custodianship of Gwenvier Derek
and your fact Gwenvier is that in winter,
we should all wear our socks outside our shoes.
- Brilliant.
- You said this 11 years ago, do you still do it?
- If I was writing my predictive newspaper,
I would have said it had changed the world
and that's how we were all doing it
since we had said this fact.
- Yeah.
- And I don't think anyone's doing it.
- Where it's not yours.
- Despite the science being on its side.
- 'Cause the stock is slipping over, right?
- Exactly, you get more grip on the ice
if you have your socks on the outside
and this was tested.
I'm going from memory in New Zealand
and I believe either they want an ignoble price for it
or it was reported by Mark Abrams in the improbable pages.
I'm pretty sure that's where I got this from.
But yeah, they found that it was an obvious thing to do
if you're on very slippery ice,
just take your socks off, put them on the outside.
- It feels like if you're wearing specialist walking shoes
with very good grip on, and maybe you shouldn't do that.
- That's true.
And you're allowed to wear extra socks on the inside.
I think the thing that people find a bit gross
is that you're not wearing anything between your foot
and your shoe.
I don't like that.
- You wear always socks with your crucks.
- Of course, of course.
I think that's in at the moment.
I mean, my kids are certainly doing it.
- Sucks with crucks. - Yeah, socks with crucks.
- Is it? - Yeah.
- It also sounds like a duck to a susbuck, doesn't it?
- Crocs and crucks was that one.
It was about another of the naked people.
- It was very period.
- Yeah.
Well cool, hey, what a great batch.
That's a killer batch of facts.
So congratulations.
You are now the custodians of these facts.
So please look after them.
Guinevere, Robert, Jay, Zachary, Harry, Michael, Heather,
and Svining.
You hopefully have your digitally printed version of this.
And if you want your own fact, again, just go to patreon.com/clubfish.
But if you rather just listen to this show
with someone who's hoping that they can get their fact read out,
podcast@ky.com, send them our way.
Andy goes through the emails.
He cherry picks the basket, brings them here.
We love reading them.
So please continue to send them along.
But for now, that's all from me, James, and Andy.
And we'll see you again on Friday,
with another episode of No Such Thing as a Fish.
But for now, bye.
(upbeat music)